Guide to the Richard L. Purdy Collection of Thomas Hardy
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Sydney C. Cockerell Papers, Series V; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  - OTHER MATERIAL
    - Theatre Programs
      - The Famous Tragedy of the Queen of Cornwall - The Corn Exchange, 1923 Nov 28 (Box 23, Folder 746)
      - Hippolytus - Balliol Players, 1926 (Box 23, Folder 747)
      - The Mellstock Quire - The Corn Exchange, 1918 Jan 31 (Box 23, Folder 748)
      - The Queen of Cornwall - Glastonbury Festival, 1924 Aug 21 (Box 23, Folder 749)
      - Tess of the D'Urbervilles - The Corn Exchange, 1924 Nov 26 (Box 23, Folder 750)
      - Tess of the D'Urbervilles - Duke of York's Theatre, 1929 Jul 17 (Box 23, Folder 751)
    - Will - Florence Hardy, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 752)
    - Will - Thomas Hardy, 1927-28 (Box 23, Folder 753)
    - Empty Envelopes, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 754)
- Non-Hardy Material, 1753-1975; Series VI; 0.75; (2 boxes)
  Series VI is divided into three sections, each arranged alphabetically by name.
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Arnold, Matthew
      - Letter to J. J. Cross, 1885 Apr 10 (Box 24, Folder 755)
      - Letter to Principal Greenwood, 1871 May 28 (Box 24, Folder 756)
      - 2 letters to H. R. Reynolds, 1869, 1885 (Box 24, Folder 757)
      - Letter to Anna Swannick, 1883 Aug 27 (Box 24, Folder 758)
    - Auden, W. H.
      - Letter to Richard L. Purdy [includes cancelled check), 1950 Oct (Box 24, Folder 759)
    - Barclay, Gorden and Celia
      - Letter to Richard L. Purdy, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 760)
    - Bonington, Richard Parkes
      - Letter to Mrs. Barnett, 1828 Sep 6 (Box 24, Folder 761)
        [with purchase and research correspondence, 1938]
    - Brooks, Van Wyck
      - 2 letters to Richard L. Purdy, 1945 (Box 24, Folder 762)
    - Browning, Robert
      - Letter to Mrs. Thomas Fitzgerald, 1888 Jun 23 (Box 24, Folder 763)
        [with research letter and transcription, 1965]
      - Letter to Mrs. Leslie Stephen, 1874 Mar 23 (Box 24, Folder 764)
        [with purchase correspondence, 1954]
      - Letter to Miss Shepherd, 1888 Aug 1 (Box 24, Folder 765)
      - Letter to Dr. E. Waring, 1887 Nov 10
        - [with clipping from Pall Mall Gazette, 1887 Nov 9, annotated by Dr. Waring]
          See: Oversize, Box 30, folder 856
      - Letter to [Thomas] Woolner, [1848?] (Box 24, Folder 766)
    - Burnett, Frances Hodgson
      - Letter to Richard L. Purdy [with autograph card and clipping], 1915 Jan 5 (Box 24, Folder 767)
    - Cotman, John S.
      - Letter to "My Dear French", 1834 Jan 4 (Box 24, Folder 768)
    - Cowper, William [cousin of the poet?]
      - Letter to Joshua Sharpe, 1753 Mar 6 (Box 24, Folder 769)
        [with purchase notes, transcription, and letter from Charles Ryskamp, 1953]
    - Davin, Dan
      - Letter to Richard L. Purdy, 1947 Aug 8 (Box 24, Folder 770)
    - de la Mare, Walter
      - 4 letters to Richard L. Purdy, 1933-34 (Box 24, Folder 771)
    - Edwards, A. H.
      - Greeting card to Richard L. Purdy, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 772)
    - Grant, [Jonathan?] H.
      - Letter to Richard L. Purdy, 1934 Jul 24 (Box 24, Folder 773)
    - Hallam, Arthur H.
      - Letter to John Kemble[?], n.d. (Box 24, Folder 774)
      - Letter to Edward Moxon, [1831 Jul 15] (Box 24, Folder 775)
        [with purchase correspondence]
      - Letter to Edward Spedding, [1831?] (Box 24, Folder 776)
    - James, Henry
      - 3 letters to John Walter Cross, 1880-[1901?] (Box 24, Folder 777)
        [with transcriptions and research correspondence, 1965]
    - Linton, Eliza Lynn
      - Letter to Mrs. Smallpiece [fragment], n.d. (Box 24, Folder 778)
    - Meredith, George
      - Letter to K. Cornish, 1861 Mar 19 (Box 24, Folder 779)
        [with purchase notes]
    - Pratt, E. J.
      - 2 letters to Richard L. Purdy, 1944-45 (Box 24, Folder 780)
    - Rae, W. Fisher
      - Letter to Mrs. Shaw-LeFevre, 1896 May 13 (Box 24, Folder 781)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano
      - Letter to L. A. Purdy, 1918 May 21 (Box 24, Folder 782)
    - Rossetti, Christina
      - Letter to [Mrs. Bristow], 1889 Dec 6 (Box 24, Folder 783)
      - Letter to "Sir", 1866 Jan 4 (Box 24, Folder 784)
      - Letter to [S. Susan Spencer?], 1893 Dec (Box 24, Folder 785)
        [removed from Richard L. Purdy's copy of The Face of the Deep by Christina Rossetti]
    - Rossetti, Dante Gabriel
      - 11 letters to Theodore Watts-Dunton [including one addressed to The Athenaeum ], 1874-81 (Box 24, Folder 786)
        [includes transcriptions and research correspondence, 1977]
    - Sassoon, Siegfried
      - Letter to Desmond MacCarthy, 1948 Apr 1 (Box 24, Folder 787)
    - Smith, George
      - 2 letters to Leslie Stephen, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 788)
    - Stephen, Leslie
      - 27 letters to George Smith, 1866-74, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 789)
        [with research correspondence, 1948]
    - Strachey, Lytton
      - Letter to Arthur Rogers, 1926 Jun 23 (Box 24, Folder 790)
    - Swinburne, Algernon
      - Letter to Matthew Arnold, [1808] Jul 3 (Box 24, Folder 791)
        [with transcription and purchase notes]
    - Tennyson, Alfred Lord
      - 4 letters to Robert Monteith, [ca. 1850-54] (Box 24, Folder 792)
        [with auction clippings and transcription and letter from Karl Schreiber, 1953 Dec 7]
    - Tennyson, Emily
      - Letter to Henry Longfellow, 1868 Jul 18 (Box 24, Folder 793)
        [with copy of "The Song of the Alma River" by Emily Tennyson, and purchase notes]
    - Trollope, Anthony
      - Letter to the editor of The Athenaeum, 1856 Feb 5 (Box 24, Folder 794)
        [includes research correpondence and "'Trollope and Little Dorrit'" by Bradford A. Booth, 1948]
    - Ward, Mary Augusta [Mrs. Humphry]
      - Letter to R. Garde, 1914 Apr 26 (Box 24, Folder 795)
    - Wharton, Edith
      - Letter to Richard L. Purdy [with note], 1933 Aug 16 (Box 24, Folder 796)
    - Wilkie, Thomas
      - Letter to Richard B. Sheridan, 1801 Jul 11 (Box 24, Folder 797)
  - WRITINGS
    - Bell, Henry Glassford
      - "Mary Queen of Scots" [pamphlet, privately printed for Thomas Hardy], [1927] (Box 24, Folder 798)
        [includes purchase correspondence, 1938]
    - Browning, Robert (1812-1889)
      - "The blind man to the maiden said...," holograph (Box 24, Folder 799)
        [translation of 4 stanzas of "Es wird Kommen" by Wilhelmine von Hillern]
      - 10 manuscript fragments from the collection of Everard Meynell, [ca. 1880s] (Box 24, Folder 800)
        [includes a part of the prose version of Red Cotton Night-Cap Country; notes on the second trip to Italy; quotations; a medical recipe; verse; and an exhibition announcement sent from Browning to Alfred Hunt, 1881 Mar 24]
      - The Ring and the Book, notes, holograph (Box 24, Folder 801)
    - Browning, Robert (1782-1866, father of the poet)
      - "Hamelin," [poem], holograph, 1843 Mar (Box 24, Folder 802)
    - Hewlett, Maurice
      - "The Next Election but One," [lecture], holograph, ca. 1924 (Box 24, Folder 803)
        [with transcription and letter from Hilda Hewlett, 1924]
      - EMPTY FOLDER (Box 24, Folder 804)
    - Reed, Henry
      - "The Auction Sale," galley, corrected, 1960 Jul 23 (Box 24, Folder 805)
      - "Bocca di Magra"
        - typescript, [1975] (Box 24, Folder 806)
        - proof, corrected, [1975]
        - printed version, Listener, 1975 Apr 24
      - "Chard Whitlow" [parody of T. S. Eliot], published version, The New Stateman and Nation, 1941 May 10 (Box 24, Folder 806a)
      - "A Good Dream," holograph, 1969 Mar 14 (Box 24, Folder 807)
      - "The Internal," typescript, photocopy, 1969 Jun 27 (Box 24, Folder 808)
      - Radio play adaptation of Summer by Romain Weingarten, typescript, photocopy, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 809)
    - Swinburne, Algernon
      - "Elegy 1869-1891" [poem], holograph fragment, [1892?] (Box 24, Folder 810)
        [includes transcription and purchase notes]
    - Tennyson, Alfred Lord
      - "In Memoriam," [section: "Thou comest, much-wept-for..."], holograph, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 811)
        [includes auction and research correspondence, 1944-75]
      - "Score of Two Voices" [poem], holograph fragment, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 812)
    - Victoria, Queen
      - Speech on the Opening of the Royal Albert Hall, holograph [in the hand of Lt. General Grey], 1867 (Box 24, Folder 813)
        [with purchase notes, 1958]
  - MISCELLANEOUS
    - Album, containing greeting and business promotional cards, ca. 1900 (Box 25, Folder 814)
    - Folding verses for children, decorated with watercolors: "A lion roaring from his den..." and "The Serpent tempts and Eve consents...", [ca. 1700s] (Box 25, Folder 815)
    - King, James
      - Calling card, with notes, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 816)
    - Meredith, George
      - Receipt, signed, from John Chapman, 1857 Oct (Box 25, Folder 817)
    - Ripert-Monclar, André [Victor Amédée], marquis de
      - Items from an album, [ca. 1840s] (Box 25, Folder 818)
      - [Includes: pencil drawing of Amélie, [18]37 Jul 17; pencil drawing of Victor Hugo by André de Ripert-Monclar; Permission slip to visit the Royal Castle for [Robert?] Browning; and advertisement for "Kean" at the Teatro de' Fiorentini, 1844 Oct 13]
      - Portrait by William Brockedon [chalk on paper], [18]35 (Box 25, Folder 818a ptg)
    - Rossetti, Dante Gabriel
      - Etching [print] for The Early Italian Poets ], [1861] (Box 25, Folder 819)
      - Photographs of tombstone, graveyard and bungalow, Birchington-on-Sea (Box 25, Folder 820)
    - Wagner, Richard
      - Photograph, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 821)
- Materials removed from Printed Items, 1903-80, n.d.; Series VII; 0.42; (1 box)
  Series VII contains materials previously contained in printed items, which have been cataloged separately. This list records their provenance. Unless indicated otherwise, all notes are likely in the hand of Richard L. Purdy.
  - WORKS BY THOMAS HARDY
    - Note, 1959 Jun 23 (Box 32, Folder 858)
      Removed from: Hardy, Thomas. Address delivered by Hardy on laying the commemoration stone of the new Dorchester Grammar School (Cambridge: University Press, 1927)
    - Note and letter [incomplete] from Maggs Bros. to Howard Bliss, 1930 Sep 8 (Box 32, Folder 859)
      Removed from: Hardy, Thomas. The Benighted Travellers (Ormskirk [England]: W.A. Guest, 1886-1887)
    - Note, 1929 Sep 1 (Box 32, Folder 860)
      Removed from: Hardy, Thomas. Compassion... (Dorchester, Dorset: Henry Ling, 1924)
    - Note, 1929 Aug 12 (Box 32, Folder 861)
      Removed from: Hardy, Thomas. A Defence of Jude the Obscure (Edinburgh: Dunedin Press, 1928)
    - Note, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 862)
      Removed from: Hardy, Thomas. Desperate Remedies (New York: George Munro's Sons, [1888])
    - Letter to Thomas Hardy from Arthur L. Salmon, 1909 Oct 4 (Box 32, Folder 863)
      Removed from: Hardy, Thomas. Desperate Remedies (London: Ward & Downey, 1889)
    - Note, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 864)
      Removed from: Hardy, Thomas. The Dynasts... (London: Macmillan and Co., 1903)
    - Presentation note from Mr. and Mrs. Thomas Hardy to Mr. and Mrs. Paul Semperley, 1924 Dec (Box 32, Folder 865)
      Removed from: Hardy, Thomas. A Reminiscence (Cambridge: University Press, 1927)
    - Notes [by Thomas Hardy indicating passages in Homer?] and exhibition label (Box 32, Folder 866)
      Removed from: Hardy, Thomas. A Group of Noble Dames (London: Edward Joseph Mansfield, 1890)
    - Letter of presentation from Florence Hardy, 1934 Oct (Box 32, Folder 867)
      Removed from: Hardy, Thomas. An Indiscretion in the Life of an Heiress (London: privately printed, 1934)
    - Note, 1948 Aug (Box 32, Folder 868)
      Removed from: Hardy, Thomas. Jude the Obscure [German] (Stuttgart: Deutsche Verlags-Anstalt, 1897)
    - Note, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 869)
      Removed from: Hardy, Thomas. Life's Little Ironies... (London: Osgood, McIlvaine, & Co., 1896)
    - Notes, 1948-49 (Box 32, Folder 870)
      Removed from: Hardy, Thomas. The Mayor of Casterbridge... (London: Sampson, Low, Marston, & Co. [189-?])
    - Catalog listing, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 871)
      Removed from Hardy, Thomas. Moments of Vision and Miscellaneous Verses (London: Macmillan and Co., 1917)
    - Letter from Oxford University Press to Purdy, 1955 Aug 26 (Box 32, Folder 872)
      Removed from: Hardy, Thomas. Our Cave at West Poley (London: Geoffrey Cumberlege, Oxford University Press, 1953)
    - Receipt, 1965 May 24 (Box 32, Folder 873)
      Removed from: Hardy, Thomas. Pages from the the Works of Thomas Hardy (London: Chatto & Windus, 1922)
    - Catalog listing, 1937 Mar 31 (Box 32, Folder 874)
      Removed from: Hardy, Thomas. The Play of "Saint George"... (Cambridge: University Press, 1921)
    - Letter from "George" [to Purdy?], n.d. (Box 32, Folder 875)
      Removed from: Hardy, Thomas. Plots for five unpublished short stories (London: London Magazine, 1958)
    - Letter from Robert H. Bentley of The New Republic to Purdy, 1929 Jan 15 (Box 32, Folder 876)
      Removed from: Hardy, Thomas. The Return of the Native (New York: Harper & Brothers, 1929)
    - Catalog listing, 1929 (Box 32, Folder 877)
      Removed from: Hardy, Thomas. Selected Poems of Thomas Hardy (London: Macmillan and Co., 1917)
    - Catalog listing and note, 1956, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 878)
      Removed from: Hardy, Thomas. Song of the Soldiers (London: Clement Shorter, 1914)
    - Note, 1948 Aug (Box 32, Folder 879)
      Removed from: Hardy, Thomas. Tess of D'Urbervilles [German] (Stuttgart: Deutsche Verlags-Anstalt, 1897)
    - Note, 1948 Aug (Box 32, Folder 880)
      Removed from: Hardy, Thomas. Under the Greenwood Tree... (London: Tinsley Bros., 1876)
    - Note, 1941 Jun (Box 32, Folder 881)
      Removed from: Hardy, Thomas. The Woodlanders (London: Macmillan and Co., 1887)
  - WORKS BY OTHERS
    - Note and exhibition label (Box 32, Folder 882)
      Removed from: Aeschylus. The Tragedies of Aeschylus (London: Whitaker & Co., 1855)
    - Catalog Listing and Receipt, 1932-33 (Box 32, Folder 883)
      Removed from: Allen, Grant. The General's Will (London: Richard Butterworth, 1893)
    - Notes and catalog listing (Box 32, Folder 884)
      Removed from: Arnold, Matthew. Cromwell: a Prize Poem, Recited in the Theatre, Oxford, June 28, 1843 (Oxford: J. Vincent, 1843)
    - Catalog listing, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 885)
      Removed from: Arnold, Matthew. Empedocles on Etna: and Other Poems (London: B. Fellowes, 1852)
    - Note and catalog listing (Box 32, Folder 886)
      Removed from: Arnold, Matthew. Poems (London: Longman, Brown, Green, and Longmans, 1854)
    - Letters from the Royal Society of Arts and donation form from the Fund for the Preservation of Ancient Cottages, 1927 (Box 32, Folder 887)
      Removed from: Baldwin, Stanley. The Preservation of Ancient Cottages: an Appeal (London: Royal Society of Arts, 1927)
    - Note, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 888)
      Removed from: Ballades & Rondeaus, Chants Royal, Sestinas, Villandelles, & c. (London: Walter Scott, 1887)
    - Newspaper clipping with note by Thomas Hardy, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 889)
      Removed from: Barnes, William. A Grammar and Glossary of the Dorset Dialect (Berlin: A. Asher & Co., 1863)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1903, 1957 (Box 32, Folder 890)
      Removed from: Barnes, William. Select Poems of William Barnes [chosen by Thomas Hardy] (London: Henry Frowde, 1908)
    - Note from Alfred Pope to Purdy, 1928 Jul 1 (Box 32, Folder 891)
      Removed from: Bartlett, Richard Grosvenor. A Book of Remembrance... (London: Chiswick Press, 1919)
    - Note, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 892)
      Removed from: Book of Common Prayer (London: A.R. Mowbray & Co., [1911?])
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 893)
      Removed from: Book of Common Prayer (London: Novello & Co., 189-?)
    - Letter from UVA Library to Purdy, 1943 Nov 2 (Box 32, Folder 894)
      Removed from: The Book of the Poe Centenary...(Charlottesville, VA: University of Virginia, 1909)
    - Catalog listing and receipt, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 895)
      Removed from: Boughton, Rutland. The Famous tragedy of the Queen of Cornwall, (London: Joseph Williams Company Ltd., 1926)
    - Notes on G. F. Ryves, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 896)
      Removed from: Brenton, Edward Pelham. The Naval History of Great Britain... (London: Henry Colburn, 1837)
    - Postcard to Purdy from Warner Barnes and unused sheet of stationery: "29, De Vere Gardens. W.", 1980, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 897)
      Removed from: Browning, Robert. The Ring and the Book (London: Smith, Elder & Co., 1868-1869)
    - Catalog listing, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 898)
      Removed from: Buchanan, Robert Williams. The Devil's Case: a Bank Holiday Interlude (London: Robert Buchanan, 1894)
    - Bookmark, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 899)
      Removed from: Burns, Robert. The Letters of Robert Burns (London: Walter Scott, 1887)
    - Catalog listing with added notes, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 900)
      Removed from: Clough, Arthur Hugh. Letters and Remains of Arthur Clough (London: Spottiswoode & Co., 1865)
    - Catalog listing, 1945 (Box 32, Folder 901)
      Removed from: Dante Alighieri. La Divina Comedia (Livorno: Tommaso Masi & Co., 1807-1813 [i.e. 1806-1813])
    - Note, [1953?] (Box 32, Folder 902)
      Removed from: De la Mare, Walter. The Hostage (London: Selwyn & Blount, 1925)
    - Note and transcribed letters from Thomas Hardy to "Em" (1894) and to "Dear Madam" (1895 Dec 22) with notes by Purdy (Box 32, Folder 903)
      Removed from: Egerton, George. Keynotes (London: Elkin Mathews & John Lane, 1893)
    - Note, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 904)
      Removed from: Erlanger, Frederic, baron d'. Tess: a Drama in Four Acts (London: G. Ricordi & Co., 1909)
    - Catalog listing, 3 letters from Maggs Bros. Ltd. to Purdy and receipt, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 905)
      Removed from: copy of Father Christmas
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 906)
      Removed from: Feller, F.E.. A New Pocket Dictionary, English and German...(Leipzig: B.G. Teubner, 1874)
    - Note and letter from Kate Hardy to James Sparks, 1921 Apr 8 (Box 32, Folder 907)
      Removed from: Frith, W.P.. My Autobiography and Reminiscences (London: Richard Bentley and Son, 1888)
    - Catalog listing, 1963 May 27 (Box 32, Folder 908)
      Removed from: The Golden Treasury... (Cambridge: Macmillan & Co., 1865)
    - Note, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 909)
      Removed from: Selected epigrams from the Greek Anthology... (New York: Longmans, Green, & Co., 1911)
    - Notes and letter from -- Gilbert to Thomas H. O. Motter, 1935 Nov 17, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 910)
      Removed from: Hallam, Arthur Henry. Remains, in Verse and Prose, of Arthur Henry Hallam (London: W. Nicol, 1834)
    - Newspaper clipping, 1930 Apr 17 (Box 32, Folder 911)
      Removed from: Hardy, Florence Emily. The Later Years of Thomas Hardy (London: Macmillan and Co., 1930)
    - Copy of letter from F. A. Hedgcock to Edmund Gosse, with notes, [1911?], n.d. (Box 32, Folder 912)
      Removed from: Hedgcock, Frank Arthur. Essai de critique, Thomas Hardy, penseur et artiste (Paris: Librairie Hachette & Cie., [1911])
    - Catalog listing, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 913)
      Removed from: Henault, Charles Jean Francois. Nouvel abrégé chronologique de l'histoire de France... (Paris: Chez Prault Père et al, 1775)
    - Note, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 914)
      Removed from: Housman, A.E.. A Shropshire Lad (London: Grant Richards, 1900)
    - Note, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 915)
      Removed from: Infantry Sword Exercise... (London: W. Clowes & Sons [1873])
    - 2 Leaves, lock of [artificial?] hair, pressed flower, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 916)
      Removed from: Jones' Series of Engravings... (London: Jones & Co., [184-?])
    - Note, 1948 Aug (Box 32, Folder 917)
      Removed from: Kinglake, Alexander William. Eothen (London: George Newnes, Limited, 1898)
    - 3 Newspaper clippings, notes, and one blank postcard from Mrs. Thomas Hardy, 1928-65, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 918)
      Removed from: Lea, Hermann. Thomas Hardy's Wessex (London: Macmillan & Co., 1913)
    - Photograph [labeled: J C Troxell May 1956], 2 blank postcards, 1956 May, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 919)
      Removed from: Marillier, H. C.. Dante Gabriel Rosetti: an Illustrated Memorial... (London: George Bell and Sons, 1899)
    - Letter from R. M. Johnston to Thomas Hardy, 1910 Nov 11 (Box 32, Folder 919a)
      Removed from: Napoleon I. The Corsican, a Diary of Napoleon's Life in his own Words (Boston: Houghton Mifflin Company, 1910)
    - Photograph of unveiling of Hardy statue, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 920)
      Removed from: Omar Khayyam. Rub'aiy'at of Omar Khayy'am, the Astronomer-Poet of Persia (London: Macmillan and Co., 1905)
    - Note, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 921)
      Removed from: Pardon, George Frederick. Billiards, Its Theory and Practice... (London: Ward, Lock, and Tyler, [1876])
    - Catalog listing, 1963 May 27 (Box 32, Folder 922)
      Removed from: Penley, Aaron. A System of Water-Colour Painting... (London: Winsor and Newton, 1857)
    - Catalog listing, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 923)
      Removed from: Pinero, Arthur Wing, Sir. The Squier (London: J. Miles & Co., 1881)
    - Note [from bookseller?], n.d. (Box 32, Folder 924)
      Removed from: Poetae Scenici Graeci... (Lipsiae: Libraria Weidmannia, 1841)
    - Invitation to exhibition and calling card from Purdy, [1928] Apr 20, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 925)
      Removed from: Purdy, Richard Little. Thomas Hardy, 1840-1928: Catalog of a Memorial Exhibition... (New Haven: Yale University Library, 1928)
    - Receipt, 1930 Aug 8 (Box 32, Folder 926)
      Removed from: The Queen's Carol... (London: "Daily Mail", 1905)
    - Note & catalog listing, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 927)
      Removed from: Rossetti, Christina Georgina. Speaking Likenesses (London: Macmillan and Co., 1874)
    - Letter to Thomas Hardy from T. Fisher Unwin, 1904 Jul 1 (Box 32, Folder 928)
      Removed from: Rutherford, Mark. The Autobiography of Mark Rutherford (London: T. Fisher Unwin, [1904])
    - Catalog pages, notes and letter from Frank Hollings to Purdy, 1926, 1978, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 929)
      Removed from: Scott, Walter, Sir. The Field of Waterloo: a poem (Edinburgh: James Ballantyne & Co., 1815)
    - Thomas Hardy's calling card, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 930)
      Removed from: Shakespeare, William. Shakespeare's tragedy of King Lear (London: J. M. Dent & Co., 1895)
    - Catalog listing & note, 1945, 1956 (Box 32, Folder 931)
      Removed from: Shelley, Percy Bysshe. Adonais: an Elegy on the Death of John Keats... (Cambridge: W. Metcalfe, 1829)
    - Letter from A. Halcrow to Purdy, letter from A. McK. Terhune to Purdy, photocopy of sample of Lucy Fitzgerald's handwriting, catalog listing and notes, 1949, 1950, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 932)
      Removed from: Tennyson, Alfred Tennyson, Baron. Tiresias and Other Poems (London: Macmillan & Co., 1885)
    - Notes, exhibition label, receipt, letter from Macmillan Co. to Purdy, letter from Charles Tennyson to Purdy (with carbon copy), letter from Hodgson & Co. to Purdy, letter from Leslie Chaundy of Dulau & Company Ltd. to Purdy, 1940-42, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 933)
      Removed from: Tennyson, Hallam Tennyson, Baron. Materials for a Life of A.T.... [Eng. ?: 1894 or 1895?]
    - Note, 1948 Aug (Box 32, Folder 934)
      Removed from: issue of The Theatre... (London: Charles Dickens & Evans, [1882])
    - Invitation, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 935)
      Removed from: The Ways of God... (London: Gowans & Gray, 1907)
    - Clippings and notes and letter from Hardy to Sydney Cockerell, 1912 Nov 15, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 936)
      Removed from: Webb, A.P.. A Bibliography of the Works of Thomas Hardy (London: Frank Hollings, 1916)
    - Note, 1948 Aug (Box 32, Folder 937)
      Removed from: Wharton, Edith. A Backward Glance (D. Appleton-Century Company, 1934)